# Ronny Martin Condor Iturrizaga

Bachelor's degree in Economics from the Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos. Interest in research on development economics, applied microeconomics, education, and poverty. Currently, Research Associate at IPA. Experience in instrument design and fieldwork management.

# EDUCATION

# Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos, Lima, Perú

Faculty of Economics Sciences, Bachelor in Economics Belonging to the tenth highest.

March 2016-December 2020

#### EXPERIENCE

### Innovations for Poverty Action (IPA)

Research Associate Oct 2021 - present

Research design and instruments review for a Randomized Controlled Trial (RCT) of Belizean students that aims to increase the intention to study STEAM careers.

Research Analyst

December 2020-September 2021

Collaboration in projects about Early Childhood Development in El Salvador and Entrepreneurial Mindset Training in Ecuador. Support in instruments review, data management, fieldwork monitoring and data analysis.

#### Office of the Comptroller General of Peru

Consultant

July 2020-November 2020

Collaboration in the project called "Improvement of Control Services for the Effective, Preventive and Enabling Control of Public Management" financed by the Inter-American Development Bank and the Office of the Comptroller General of Peru.

#### Videnza Consultores

In tern

January 2020-July 2020

Writing quantitative results of economic studies commissioned by private, public, and international institutions. Data collection and data management. Moreover, support in qualitative research projects.

# TEACHING

### Teaching Assistant

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

March 2019-July 2019

- Economics of Distribution (Github repo)
- Econometrics I (Introductory Econometrics)

# ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

# La Rotonda Blog

Director

April 2020 - Present

La Rotonda is a non-profit organization whose main objective is the free dissemination of knowledge in the different branches of Economics and the promotion of oportunities across diverse groups in Peru.

#### Workshop speaker

Universidad Nacional Mayor de San Marcos

2019-2021

- Topic: Towards other approaches: The contribution of Georgescu-Roegen's bioeconomy.
- Topic: Introductory Stata course. (Github repo)

# SKILLS

- Languages: Spanish (native) English (advanced)
- Software: Stata, R, LATEX, Markdown, Git, Survey CTO, Kobo Toolbox.

# WORK IN PROGRESS

- Ethnic inequality: a look from Peruvian microdata (with Guiliana Campos)
- The effect of trade openness on poverty and inequality in Peru: a micro-simulation analysis
- Does innovation have an effect in development? Evidence from Peru

# — COMPLEMENTARY COURSES

# **US** Research Staff Training

Abdul Latif Jameel Poverty Action Lab (J-PAL)

present

#### Data for Better Lives: A New Social Contract

World Bank Group in edX (WBGx)

present

#### Online MicroMaster in Data, Economics, and Development Policy

Massachusetts Institute Technology in edX (MITx)

Sep 2021

Courses completed: Microeconomics and Data Analysis for Social Scientists

#### Preparation of quantitative research proposals

Consorcio de investigación económica y social (CIES)

June 2020

#### Designing a Multidimensional Poverty Index

Oxford Poverty & Human Development Initiative (OPHI)

April 2020